Rishu Srivastava (1) Featured

Associate Consultant seeking roles in Software Engineering, Salesforce Development, CPQ, Project Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, Agile Methodology, Application Support, Core Java, Triggers, Apex, CSS, C



Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 0 Month(s) Current Designation: Associate Consultant

Current Company: Wipro Notice Period: Currently Serving Notice Period Current Location: Delhi Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Delhi / NCR, Bahrain, Dubai

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Associate Consultant, Software Developer, Software Engineering, Salesforce Developer, CPQ, Project Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, Agile

Methodology, Application Support, Core Java, Triggers, Apex, CSS, C

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

Salesforce Certified Admin and Developer with approx. 4+ years of experience in development and configuration on the Salesforce.com platform and development in Java using Agile/Scrum methodologies. Experience in development of Apex classes/test classes, Process Builder, Workflow, Validation Rules, Security, Lightning Component, Triggers, Batch jobs, Customization and configuration. Accomplished development with a powerful record of maintaining client satisfaction and a proven independent worker, multitasker, and team player.

Work Experience

Wipro as Associate Consultant Sep 2019 to Till Date

Wipro as Associate Consultant Sep 2019 to Sep 2019

Worked with different company developer's team for requirement gathering and implementation.

Learnt CPQ here and started working on that.

Created a mechanism to do bulk data load in Salesforce staging tables and then basis the business logic dispersing the data in other different tables.

Creating dynamic lightning record form basis templates for which the fields and templates mapping is stored in Custom Metadata.

Got to develop Lightning screens, having a complex relationship between Quote, QuoteLines and Special Discount (custom object).

Wrote triggers on CPQ objects like Product Options, Quotelines, etc.

Handled a scenario where due to a process builder update '101-Too many SOQL Query' exception was coming in trigger method because of legacy design.

Worked on Google Maps API integration with salesforce, with different- different scenarios.

Used apex-map and lightning map also to implement some use-case.

Created several Lightning Web Components.

Created Custom Exception handling object and classes. A record gets created in salesforce org if an exception occurs and also triggers an email on its creation.

Worked on Salesforce site to manage cases for guest users. Managed their login as well.

alone had to manage and coordinate with different vendor's team as I was the only developer from our company side for the client.

Worked as a Release Manager as well, where I have to deploy the changes to higher environment using Changeset and then Gearset.

Team Size: 5(Scrum Team).

Worked with the user group for requirement gathering throughout the planning and implementation.

Defined Org wide default to restrict access from users.

Created Data Validation rules and Formulas as per business requirement.

Created page layouts, search layouts to organize fields, custom links, related lists and other components on a record detail and edit pages.

Created Process Builder to invoke Apex class method in order to trigger the existing Assignment Rules.

Customized the existing Apex code logic after impact analysis to prevent the execution to hit CPU time limit error.

Learnt and created Lightning Web Component (LWC).

Worked on VS Code to deliver and deploy the code.

Managed multiple sandbox environments.

Impact analysis of Spring'20 release and Critical Updates came, and then fixing them.

Team Size: 5(Scrum Team).

TCS as System Engineer Nov 2016 to Aug 2019

Created Service Console App in order to make things easy for the internal user to register Cases for the customers.

Worked on Service Cloud functionality for Case creation, Routing, Case Feed.

Create and manage workflow, complex formula, validation rule, trigger and process builder.

Worked on Apex classes, Triggers, Lightning Component, etc.

Used Custom Metadata and Custom Setting for storing and then retrieving the values as per business needs.

Establish maintain and enhance security using profile, role, hierarchy and sharing model.

Used SOQL & SOSL with consideration to Governor Limits for data manipulation needs of the application using platform

Practicing CICD- Continuous development, delivering changes to higher environment.

Worked on microservices architecture by implementing the functionality of Financial Profile in Java then later integrating it with Salesforce.

Worked on Unit Testing and Code Coverage for triggers and Classes.

Designing of custom Objects, Custom fields Page Layouts, Record types etc.

Created new User Accounts and assigned Profiles as per their role in role hierarchy.

Worked on data migration (Both Import and Export) to and from salesforce org.

Also, did development using Java, SQL, and REST.

Used SonarQube, Fortify to maintain code quality.

Team Size: 8(Scrum Team).

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from noida institute of engineering & technology, greater noida in 2016

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Platform Developer 1

Administrator

Microsoft Certified Professional: Software Development Fundamentals

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Apex, Triggers, Core Java, C#, C	
JavaScript, CSS, VS Code	
Process builder, Workflow, Formula	
Agile/Scrum Methodology	

Languages Known

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=1448ec94234bc98093322c70e247f0f30d5a58544d1b5a42071347510c...

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak	
English					
Hindi					

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time